everybody tells you to backst but why
should you do it and how to actually do
it and what software to use what data to
gather how to gather your data where to
log it in we have all of those questions
welcome to the trading fanatic channel
in this video it's going to be all about
back TST how to do it different ways to
do it how to gather data and everything
you need to know about and I'm also
going to show you some softwares and I'm
going to give you a tool so actually go
ahead back test gain data about your
trading strategy and of course through
back testing you're going to become a
better Trader and learn your strategy in
and out so if you're excited about it
let's get into it let's say you bought a
course or you watch the Youtube video
and usually educators are going to
illustrate their point better by picking
textbook scenarios from the markets in
order to illustrate their point and at
the moment when you see that video and
when you see those examples you get that
pink aha moment and you're like wow this
really makes sense I really understand
this concept I'm just going to go ahead
and apply it in the markets it looks
pretty easy I understand it but then
tomorrow or on the same same day you go
on the markets and you try to find
examples or you even life trade what you
learned but it doesn't seem to work you
get losses and you get a little bit
confused maybe you go back to watch that
video again and again it makes sense but
again you just go on the live markets or
you just try to find some examples on
the charts and nothing seems to work so
then what you do is all right this video
doesn't work this course doesn't work
I'm going to find another one so what
that is called is strategy hoping and
why do Traders do this well they're too
lazy to actually sit down study back
test apply what they learn over a long
period of time and usually professional
Traders use data backed strategies so
they have a strategy that is backed up
by data over one or two years of back
testing that actually proves there is a
positive Edge within that strategy so
that they know over a long term they're
winning so that is the difference
between losing and winning Traders
winning Traders have data over their
strategies while losing Traders they
just study something they try to go
apply it it doesn't work immediately and
then then they try to find the next
thing and in order to transition from a
losing to a winning Trader you have to
back test so let me tell you what
actually back testing is as for the
basics back testing means simply going
back in time throughout past data to
pretty much test whether your strategy
worked in the past because it is said
that if a strategy produces positive
results in the past throughout a longer
period of time well it is most likely
going to yield the positive return also
in the future and again pay attention I
say over a longer period of time which
could like minimum 6 months I would even
go to back to the strategy for a year
because 3 months you can be winning in
the next one month you can blow all of
your earnings right so you got to make
sure to put it to the pressure test of
all different market conditions so again
never go forward without back testing a
strategy or a concept you want to use
now listen carefully because this is the
most important benefit of back testing
it serves the purpose of gathering data
regarding your trading strategy and the
beauty of it is that you can do it
really fast I mean if you want to test
one month of live data so if you want to
sit through one month of price action in
the live markets well again you got to
wait for 30 days but in back testing you
can just test one month of data for one
hour so you get to really gather data
fast so you can very quickly prove
whether your strategy actually works but
now when it comes to data I'm right now
going to give you 10 important pieces of
information that you should gather and
then of course I'm going to give you a
template for doing that so pay close
attention all right so the first
important piece of data you need is very
simple and very basic which is your
final result did you lose money or did
you win money if you lost money just
throw a strategy in the trash because
why would you continue testing something
that costed you money and if you
actually did win money well take into
account the percentage you return
because maybe there is something better
you can tweak later that is going to
yield you a better result second of all
is how many trades did you lose and how
many trades did you win which is going
to determine your win rate and you
pretty much do this by taking how many
trades you won out of all the trades you
took so if you took 100 trades and you
want 50 trades you divide either 100 by
50 or 50 by 100 and you're going to get
that 50% win rate now don't do the maths
by yourself I'm going to share an
amazing tool with you uh within the
nocean dashboard that automatically
calculates your win rate for you also
including break even trades now the
third thing you want to know is your
average R reward ratio you really want
to find out that sweet spot for your
strategy so that you know what is the
average RIS to reward that it is
returning and I want you to measure your
maximum rest reward on every single
trade and I want to measure your minimum
which is not that important why do I
make you measure the maximum roed word
of every trade because let's say you're
taking two r on every trade but on
average all of your trades are hitting
like 5 to six R so when you have that
information then of course you can make
a decision to increase your rward ratio
and of course make more money so it is
very important to F the median or the
average RIS reward ratio of your
strategy fourth and very important data
point this is this is your average
stop-loss size so what you simply have
to do is when you take a trade just
logging the stop- loss size you're
taking because again at the end of your
back testing session you're going to see
what is your usual or average stop- loss
so that when you encounter a trade life
if the stop loss is way too big from
what you're usually using maybe you skip
the trade if it's small maybe it's it's
better again you have to know your
average stop- loss size and of course
then you have to find ways in order to
either decrease it or increase it
depending on what you want to do fifth
point that not a lot of you do is to
take note of your best trading days and
I know you're going to be surprised but
you're literally going to see that for
example Mondays are your best days and
of course the sixth tip is to also Mark
up your worst days because again you
want to know on which days you're most
likely to lose money for me those are
Thursdays I don't know why but I lose
money on Thursday so guess what I don't
trade on Thursday I don't know why but
again throughout my back testing I see
that on Thursday I lost much more than I
want over a longer period of time so
again G this gives me the edge to skip
Thursdays to actually recharge myself
and to come back stronger on Friday
which is one of my best trading days
number seven is the max trades per day I
want you to back test like you're doing
in a textbook scenario I want you to
take every single trade that you see in
the live market so then of course you
know for example the maximum trades that
I ever took was six trades because when
you have that number you know later how
to tweak your risk parameters because
for example you might say oh I'm only
going to take two trades per day but
what if those first two trades are
losses and then the third trade is a win
right and this is why you really have to
first back test see what is the maximum
amount of Trades you can take per day so
that you know also how to tweak your
risk parameters if you risk like 2% per
trade and you lose two trades in a row
well you're down quite a lot but if you
know that on average you take six trades
per day then of course you're going to
decrease your risk a little bit so that
you allow more bullets to strike
throughout the day which brings me to
point number eight which is the max
losses you have per day so what is the
maximum amount of losses you're going to
be taking per day which of course is
going to show you like what kind of
losing streak you can get into or when
should you stop trading because if you
find out that some days you can take
four to five losses in a row then maybe
you decide okay well if I took three
losses in a row or four then I'm just
going to stop and not go even forward so
again take note of that the other point
you want to also Mark out is your max
losing streak and that is extremely
important because if you know that for
example in your back testing you had a
period in which you lost 12 trades in a
row which happens with strategies of
like 30 to 40 to 50% win rate it is very
possible you lose like more than 10
trades in a row but if you actually have
this in your data when you're life
trading and if you lose a trade and then
second and third and Fifth and fourth
and sixth and like oh you're not going
to be panicking because you know in back
testing your maximum losing streak is 12
trades and you also know that longterm
you're going to get on top so take note
of your maximum losing streak and also
opposite take note of your maximum
winning streak how many trades did you
win in a row on a maximum basis because
then you know for example if on average
you take five winners in a row then you
might know like if if you take four if
you take five winners in a row in the
live markets well you might start
expecting that next loss and I know it
sounds strange you just got to keep
showing up but having that data to
support you well you know okay I'm on a
five trade winning streak well most
likely I'm going to take a loss and
you're actually prepared and finally I
want you to actually get granular with
your trading strategy and by granular I
mean dive even deeper what you can also
look for is timing which session is your
best performing session for the strategy
exactly at what time because what I
found for my strategy is that it
performs the best on London open and if
I do not take my trade in those two
hours into London open then on the next
hours I'm going to lose all right and
this is actually getting granular into
the strategy and not only also looking
at the technicals so for example you can
get granular on liquidity how many of
the trades you win if the Asian session
high or low is not taken how many of the
trades you win if the session higher low
is taken right how many trades do you
win or lose if you're trading on the 50
minute how many trades do you win or
lose if you're trading on the 30 minute
you got to really get granular in order
to find those little things that are
eventually going to help you make more
profits all right I really hope you took
note of all of those data points and now
before we jump into the technicals and
actually show you how to back test with
the technicalities I want to first talk
about forward testing or also known as
paper trade and I really love this the
difference between back testing and
forward testing is that within forward
testing you're actually testing the
strategy live so listen first you have
to back test you have to really prove to
yourself that this strategy has worked
in the past but again just like in
sports you can be really good at
practice right you can be great at
practice you can be doing great results
but when competition comes in you might
freeze and you might not be able to
execute on what you actually did on the
practice right same with trading if you
performed amazing in back testing again
in back testing you're calm there is no
emotions running there is no like live
candles sticking because in live markets
you might miss the trades you might not
see the trades every single scenario is
going to be different so again you have
to spend a lot of time forward testing
the strategy in the live markets in
order to really gain that confidence and
actually the skill to execute the
strategy because back testing showed you
that it works but then of course after
receipt works you have to get better at
executing it live so if you ask me your
next step after back testing should be
to open a small Live account right so
100 $300 $500 whatever you can afford
and just trade very low risk like
0.01% or maybe even just take 0.01 lots
and what is this going to help you is to
actually get involved in the market but
with real money and real execution
because a lot of you trade demo like
screw demo you you don't need demo
because again there is no emotions it's
fake money and the transition from demo
to life is usually very painful so much
better make a little investment of a
very small amount into a live trading
account and start taking those trades
live based on your back tested strategy
but with real funds and pretty much this
is going to help you perform better
later when you start trading life with
bigger risk like 0.50% or 1% risk
because you have seen that during live
markets with low risk you actually sold
a strategy and you executed on the
strategy and you're going to be well
prepared later and often times like you
can be really profitable in back testing
but funny as it is you go on the live
markets and you get crushed and this is
pretty much because the market changes
its cycle we get some new things
developing in the world economy that
changes the market sentiment and again
your strategy all of a sudden stops
working so do not give up keep testing
for a long period of time 3 months 6
months to really see whether it works
master that strategy and again do not
spend months just back testing going
back all the way to like 2018 to back
this where it worked in two years the
only data you need is the most recent
year so get that and then get into the
live markets because it's much better to
learn from the live markets and adapt
that strategy rather than just spending
time on back test all right it's time to
get technical because I know you're here
just for that now in order to back this
properly you're going to be needing a
data Gathering tool now this is usually
training view for a lot of us but there
are also some incredible softwares like
FX Replay that allows it to actually go
back through for a lot of data and
actually to execute the strategy as you
are in real time so I'm going to talk
about two of them but for both of those
well for FX replay it gives you a lot of
data we're going to talk about in a bit
but for trading view you are going to
need some sort of a data Gathering too
like an Excel spreadsheet or also
because I really love you oh Fanatics
I'm going to give away to you an
incredible notion spreadsheet in which
you can actually include all the data
points I mentioned a little bit earlier
and not only that but again within that
notion spreadsheet you're going to get
kind of separate data points for all of
the trades you took and for every single
trade there is going to be another
little template that you can actually
enter your hard time frame middle time
frame lower time frame analysis and also
reflect on that trade and also some
incredible stuff which we're going to be
covering in a bit so as I said we can
either back test on trading view or on a
FX replay software so let's jump into
the charts and have a look at both
options all right so if you decide to
use use trading view for your back
testing there are a few things you must
know about first of all you have limited
data to go back to when you use trading
view for example if you go down to the
one minute time frame you can just get
around four to five weeks of data with
the basic plan however if you try to
back this hard time frames like let's
say 15 minute to 5 minute you can go
further back in time so for example
myself I believe I am with the most kind
of basic plan which is yeah this
Essentials plan and again like with this
thing you get absolutely everything you
need and you can see you get 10K
historical bars so I think this is
pretty much 10,000 um one minute candles
which is pretty much going to give you
how many weeks and how many days you can
go back to so again like if I just go
back to the weekly time frame you can
see that if you try to go way back in
time like this and then you go to the
one minute oops you're going to have a
data point unavailable right here so
again if you go to the weekly time frame
I do think you can get around 1 2 3 4
for five weeks of data so if you go five
weeks back and then if you go to the 1
minute time frame there we go we have
the data so make sure to keep that in
mind second point is that you're not
held accountable when you use trading
view so for example you can take trades
after they happened or you can skip
trades if they lose I used to do that
again don't lie to yourself because if
you use trading view you're going to
need honesty if you didn't see the trade
and if you miss the trade you don't
include it in your back testing just
because the trade happened but you
didn't take it it doesn't mean you have
to include it because then you're
getting into unrealistic back testing
dates okay and third of all you have to
put in the work to enter all of your
data manually into a sheet which a lot
of Traders are lazy to do so you cannot
just go on trading View and like go on
the 50-minute time frame and say okay
I'm going to take for example this short
and I'm going to take for example this
short my strategy Works no you have to
gain a lot of data and this is why I
personally make my private Menders go
back in time and give me 50 trades back
tested or live traded which then we go
together and review on a one-on-one
basis okay so with that being said as
one of the gifts in this video I have
included a notion back testing template
in the description in this video so make
sure to grab it and right now I'm going
to give you an example of how we can use
trading view uh to take trades and then
of course I'm going to show you how to
use the notion template in order to
enter your data all right so as I
explained you can go if you if you want
to test the one minute time frame you
can go back just five weeks so we have
to go for example at the beginning of
October and then of course you go on the
weekly time frame by hitting the replay
tool right there and again you need that
paid option on trading View and then
what you simply do is you perform your
top down analysis again so let's say in
this case the market broke structure to
the upside so we're bullish but then of
course the market came back it broke
structure to the downside so we're
bearish that is our supply Zone So
currently we're at a lower low we can
expect the potential pullback or of
course we can expect the continuation
okay so get real with the actual stuff
you're going to be doing when you life
trade okay then of course you drop to
the 50-minute time frame and once again
feel free to add all of your IND
indicators now the beauty of trading
view is that you can add for example the
Asian session you can add different
tools that you want to use so let's say
for example I'm just going to play
50-minute candles until the Asian
session ends and pretty much this is how
I'm going to tackle the market live
there it is Asian session has closed
Frankford is about to open so again I'm
going to see what I'm going to be
looking for well potentially to take out
the asan high and to take a short with
the trend or if we start by taking the
low knowing that we're at a lower low
I'm going to be looking for long okay so
again you pretend you're life trading
and of course you wait I can see that
the Asian range was very nicely taken so
let's say that if I get a trend change
above this guy I'm going to take a trade
and let's say you want to enter like
with a stop order right do it before it
actually happens because I suspect this
one can actually break up right now and
then of course you're going to miss the
trade okay so if you want to take a
trade don't let's just see what happens
right so there we go so don't just say
oh this Market went up well I would have
entered this trade from here no you
cannot do that okay so before you decide
to take a trade you first set your order
here or here whatever you like to set it
you set your TP let's say we're going to
go for 2 hour right and then of course
you've taken the trade then you see how
it plays out there we go take profit for
example okay so this is not a strategy
back testing VI I just want to show you
how it's done okay so now that you have
the trade maybe you just allowed for it
to play out to see what is going to
happen then what you do is you go to
your notion template so let me flick to
the other screen so that I can actually
show you so once you open it it's going
to look something like this so let me
give you a brief tutorial now first of
all you're going to click here to add a
row and of course you can say the pair
so right now we're back testing gbpusd
you click enter then of course you can
describe your strategy so let's say
we're going to be back testing a 50
minute uh swing trading right or
something like this the date so of
course we started for as you said we
started from the 1st of October so that
we know from when we're back testing in
any details right so I am going to back
test the 50 minute sell stops buy stops
buy stops above structure something like
this okay so just briefly describe what
the back testing station is about then
you you click here so again if you're
familiar with notion that is very good
to click here and you get this uh new
page then you have to click on this
template that I have prepared for you
back test template you click on that you
can make it full screen and we just wait
for this to get populated so there is
your pretty much your template here are
all of your back tests okay and there
are some details below that so let's say
for example we took our first trade so
we type trade one today uh it was Monday
okay so time of the day again go back to
the Chart what what time did we take
this trade on again based on your time
zone it's at 8:15 of course we go back
and we say me do that and we say 8 8:15
so the entry model again this was a 5050
minute counter Trend because we were
trading against the the 4 hourly Trend
so again feel free to include things how
do you include things you just click
here and for example let's say you say
30 minute counter Trend right you just
create a new one it's very easy entry
method so again did you wait for 1
minute TC did you enter with a 5 minute
TC did you wait for a 1 minute stop
sorry for a 15-minute stop order again
feel free to add anything you want right
there stop loss Pips well again if I
look at the charts the stop loss of this
trade was 14 Pips so we type 14 we type
14 we made two R and the potential R the
market made was pretty much 2.1 and then
of course you can see I've added the
formula that is automatically going to
calculate whether it's a win a loss or a
break even so again if you if you make a
break even trade okay now that's the
potential R so if you make a break even
trade right there zero it's going to
turn as a break even if you like take
minus one it's going to turn as a loss
okay then what you want to do is you go
to here and you click trade so when you
click trade uh another thing is going to
populate once again just wait for it so
there it is watch your have right here
is higher time frame Market structure
lower time frame structure and then
entry and result so here you go back to
your chart and right now you take a
screenshot of your thought process right
so again here you're going to screenshot
this or maybe you add an annotation so
say here 4 was at a lower low I expect
pullback towards 50% okay so maybe we
forgot to add our Fibonacci there's a
Fibonacci I expect the pullback and then
po it so then you click here and then
you click copy image and then you go
back to your template and you just click
contrl + V boom there's a chart now for
your lower time frame minor structure
you again go to your chart again
depending on what your middle time frame
is in this case the 50 minute we take a
screenshot on the 50 minute and again
add annotations put some intention into
your charts I entered here with a stop
order targeting right 2 R 2 R after
taking Asian low right so explain what
you did then again copy image going back
to the to the template hitting control +
V boom there it is and again keep in
mind you can also you have empty space
right there you can you can type I took
this trade because of X because of Y
okay and then of course if you have even
a lower time frame if you go to the one
minute time frame I usually put a one
minute chart down there so what this
makes you is a collection of Trades then
when you go back okay my first trade it
was a it was a true R profits okay let
me see what I actually did okay well the
4y time frame was counter Trend but the
50 minute made this I took profit here
and then I can see the market reverse so
then here you can see how everything
actually work and then again you
continue so right now after this trade
played out again based on your strategy
you just continue you go back to the F
time frame maybe you just wait for the
new day right so let's wait for a new
day right there there is the new day
well what the market did is just
massively continued to break structure
lower we're at a very big lower low
right now we're get to drop to the
50-minute time frame what is the Asian
session doing it is trending to the
downside so again I would potentially
expect a little popup and a continuation
lower or maybe a manipulation lower and
and a buy move again we can see the
market is manipulating higher right now
but in this case like for example if you
want to enter short maybe want to go to
the 5 minute and wait for a 5 minute
Trend change like this right again this
is not a strategy video so there is our
Trend change again take the trade as you
would take it live so don't just come in
right there and say oh this Market moved
down I took the trade from here no you
took it from there and again you're
let's say you're going to Target Two R
and again you allow the trade to play
out now if you're going to go break even
or anything like this or maybe if you
see it like this and you decide to close
the trade be honest okay so let's see
what happens boom boom boom boom okay so
at that's that case I would definitely
go break even because we took out like
the Asian low so the market is very
likely to pull back so in this case
again I just go break even maybe I just
put a little line to tell me and break
even and there we go we got break even
now once again qu time frame go back to
the to to your two then you do trade two
that trade was taken on Tuesday you
checked the time it was taken during
9:30 in the morning it was a uh
50-minute continuation because we traded
with the trend uh I took it with a 5
minute Trend change the stop- loss was
uh x amount of Pips in this case 15 Pips
and the result was a zero so that is a
break even trade now again you go click
here and click on trade and then you
simply add everything that you did again
okay so hopefully that's clear right now
let me actually jump a little bit deeper
into all the data here that we have so
as you go through this process of back
testing you're going to spot patterns I
promise you there are going to be things
that make an impression on you or things
that you want to uh to remove from the
trading or something that you spot is
happening that you want to add to your
trading keep those notes right there so
those are your granular in sites from
your testing so for example you spot
that a 5minute TC works better than
50-minute TC because the stop loss the
stop loss of the 50-minute TC is is is
bigger right so then you you keep note
of these things because that is
essentially what is going to shape your
trading strategy okay so here you take
note of stuff like this now when you're
ready with the back test right there
you're pretty much going to see all the
data so you're going to see here under
values how many trades you have you're
going to see your stop loss if you want
to calculate your stop loss just click
calculate and then you do average so
you're going to see what's your average
stop- loss here under the result you're
going to see what kind of result you
have here at potential r as I told you
track your track the maximum Roost to
reward that you get for the trade right
so example let's say here is three there
is this and then for example here you
can do again median or average this is
going to show you like around an average
and you're going to get a lot of date so
again total amount of Trades you have it
right there two win rate now if you
scroll a little bit down you're going to
have this win rate calculator if I try
to open it there it is so again here you
just enter your data it's a very nice
calculator so let's say you took uh 20
wins and let's say you take five break
evens and let's say you took like 18
losses that IM middle is going to tell
you how many trades you took and what is
your winning percent in this case with a
20 winners 18 losses and five break
evens you get a 46. 51% you go back to
your uh dashboard right there and of
course you are going to type your
overall win rate again let's say 46%
average trades per day now this one you
know by having a look at the days right
there so again you see you count every
single Monday Monday Monday how many
trades did you take on Monday how many
trades did you take on Tuesday right so
how many trades did do you usually take
per day maximum losses you're pretty
much going to see it here if you have
like a loss loss loss loss loss loss
then you're going to see how many you
have in cons in consecutive ones maximum
wins largest amount of Trades per day
best trading day worst trading day take
note of everything and then for your
qualitative analysis this is where I
want you to type more words right so
when was the best timing for your trades
and again this is not very uh
quantitative because again like it's
very hard to say well 12:00 is the best
time although it's possible to do that
again just type in my impression right
here type in my impression London
session was best I was taking the best
the best trades during the first two
hours of London New York didn't work for
me right so then on the next your best
days right so on the best days I found
out I traded the mo the best on Tuesday
I think because on Tuesday the market
was forming the weekly high and low and
I was able to catch the market at a very
good positioning okay any patterns that
you spotted anything that is making an
impression on you type it down and based
on all the data you gathered what is
something that you can change or you can
tweak to make this system better okay so
for me that was timing that was
liquidity that was again trading at the
right time and also increasing my risk
of reward from two to two and a half
because I found that my trades are
running a little bit more than two are
so I ended up increasing migrain rate so
again I'm going to try to right now go
and show you some of my back testing
data so that you can actually see how a
fi chart is going to look like so for
example here are some of my back testing
uh journals right there until I switched
to FX replay I was definitely using a
trading view so again like for example
if I click on one of these you're going
to see a lot of data so there it is
exactly the same thing that I'm sharing
with you the day the time the session
the entry model Pips stop entry size I
was even measuring right there if I
enter on the stop uh if I enter on the
on the trend change itself like how many
Pips is going to be did it top 10r R
rewards uh the the biggest percentage
that I got right so how do I actually
move this to the left right and then I
was actually looking for um like I was
just placing some screenshots right
there because in this case I didn't
really put uh images because I was
looking for a slightly quicker back test
right and then of course you can see if
I just go back at it right you can see
at the bottom you're going to get like
how many trades that is and then of
course you see out of 158 trades the
median stop loss is 4 Pips so I know
that based on all the trades I took four
pip stop loss is my ideal stop loss
again the result 200% uh the biggest uh
redward that the trade was running for
was 9R so again I know that if a trade
actually goes it has a very big
potential to go up 61 wins 73 losses 21
break evens again if I just go to this
to right there and if I just use the
stats I'm going to immediately tell you
my win rate there it is so I took uh 61
wins I took 73 losses 73 losses and 21
break even so there you go my win rate
is 40% which is pretty much what I'm
able to also do in the live markets
again that is pretty much reality and
again like I have a lot of these so for
example there is a recent strategy that
I was back testing so the session
strategy that is for EU and and then I
collected the Mo right again and you can
see exactly the same thing here I was
actually uh it's uh it's a strategy
based on the asan Range so I was
measuring their Asian range in terms of
Pips how many it was trending stop- loss
size daily open the targets that I was
uh looking for again feel free to add
things here if you get used to notion
you can add things that you want to
measure and again after all the testing
85 trades uh medium stop loss of 7even
Pips 68% return and again you're going
to get and you can see like the
potential was 288 per. so again it makes
me think okay what can I do better in
order to like catch a little bit more R
right and then here you can see like 34
wins 29 losses 21 break evens you can
calculate the win rate and stuff like
this so as you populate your charts
they're going to look like this and this
is what I call statistical Edge and
actually having the backest so for any
strategy that I uh that I share that I
actually work on I have the back test
and then I and then I for example roll
it out to the community right so again
there is one of our recent strategy on
the S&P 500 again I have the entry I
have the 50-minute time frame I have 51
trades and again 50% win rate 33% return
not bad this is something worth
exploring and again always go through
that Backus so this is pretty much
notion and again once again you are
going to take note of like of all the
pictures like for example if you click
on on these things you can just put a
link right and then of course that is
going to that is going to offer you uh
the link right of the picture that you
took make sure to take pictures because
if you don't well you're not going to
have the date so with that being said
this is how you do it on notion again
you just got to go back on U again again
you just got to go back on trading view
go through very carefully exactly what
you're doing on a daily basis figure out
the entry again if you want to enter on
the one minute time frame you draw your
supply Zone you go to the one minute
time frame and you wait for it okay you
don't just come in right there and just
play canos like oh the market moved or
for example if the market massively
moves lower right or let's say you took
a trade from here stop loss above and
the market hit your stop loss ah well I
wouldn't take this trade no you took it
log it in okay so with that being said
this is training view let's explore the
other option which I think it's actually
much better now if you wish to invest in
yourself and you're in your trading I
would definitely suggest you consider
getting the FX replay software I really
love this the platform is super nice
it's easy to use and it also uses our
favorite trading your charts but this
time you get not unlimited data you can
get like to 2020 2020 I believe but also
this I what I really love about this
software is that it actually keeps you
accountable if you don't take a trade
and if you don't set your order and if
you not if you don't don't executing it
you cannot go back in time right you
simply miss the trade or you take the
loss everything is logged in and you
really have to get into the zone you
really have to get intentional with your
testing because this is as Clos you can
get to live performance you execute if
the trade misses you you don't take it
if the trade hits your stop loss it's a
stop- loss if the trade misses your take
profit you cannot cheat and say oh well
I would have taken it here no so I
really love the software uh it was
actually a Community member that suggest
that I get it so we can do some uh
Community back testing station and I got
it and I also affiliate it with the FX
Replay for a 15% discount so if you want
to get this software make sure to use
the code trading fanatic 15 it's going
to give you 50% off from the from the
subscription definitely a great software
I'm also affiliated with them because
again I love them now um the only thing
that I would suggest you do here is to
also use the notion template uh because
what FX replay doesn't have is they
don't have like place to take a
screenshot so again you you definitely
test out but still you have to take
screenshots exactly at the same way I
showed you on how to do on trading okay
so let me actually show you how it works
now first this is the dashboard uh you
can create a strategy right so let's
just say we're going to do a test
strategy save so what this helps you do
is again if you have like u a strategy
want to back this for example you can
say I have two strategies right there
it's going to give you all the details
about that strategy but then you have to
create a back testing session again
account balance it's just just 10,000
pairs you have all the instruments you
want right so let's just say Euro EUR
USD there is Euro USD and now here you
have to pick your start date again you
can go back as far as 2020 I wouldn't
suggest you go back 3 years ago so let's
just start like from 2023 January let's
say we start with like um the 1st of
January so that is just you get a whole
year of data and the end date is pretty
much going to be today the strategy you
link this session to the strategy you
want to test name maybe you put in some
name description smooth candles I do
enable and when you click save it
creates your session you click here and
now you are into the live markets
exactly like the live markets now um you
have to I have some drawings right right
there you have to first of all play a
little bit with your trading view charts
because first you're going to have like
the usual trading view charts so again
check my tutorial on trading view um on
the trading view colors and everything
so again do your colors do your status
lines scales background make your tools
okay so do you actually feel at home
like you're back testing and again qu
the time frame you start doing
everything again feel free to like do
some uh session indicators like some any
time zone indicators I use the Silver
Bullet because it shows the London
session it has like indicators here it
has a lot of and I love it now again you
just do exactly the same thing you would
do in the live Mark qu structure break
up daily demand zone right there you go
with the templates everything then you
go to the 50 minute time frame right and
then what I really like about this is
that it has this goto section and then I
just click uh go to next London session
and it just Sprints the Asian range and
goes back to the London station so again
we're bullish on the 4y we took out the
Asian low so right now we can look for a
potential long trade again you can go to
the 5 minute time frame again depending
on what you're going to be trading and
the beauty of this is that you cannot
cheat right now you have have to be
looking for that for example Trend
change but you cannot cheat so there is
the trend change now it occurred here
now you have to decide what you're going
to do at this moment so are you going to
enter from here with a stop loss below
there are you going to be looking for a
pullback because that determines how
you're going to enter so let's say we're
going to be entering with a pullback
right and then you have to also pick
your TP let's say we're going to Target
2 R right there at the previous daily
high now you have to click on the two
and you place order right there and that
is the beauty of the software because
you're actually taking trades risk per
trade from the current balance position
size entry take profit stop loss
everything now here you just got to be
careful if you're entering with a limit
order you have to change this to limit
right but if you're entering exactly
from the current price you have to click
Mark again be careful and now if you
click save this sets an order so if the
market goes without us right now we're
not in the trade and if the market hits
stop loss we take the stop loss there is
no way to cheat and to lie the system so
there we go we actually got triggered
now we are in the trade and you have to
manage it you can move your stop- loss
to break even you can move your take
profit if you want to enlarge it you can
also if you want want close partials you
click close position and you can close
partials it is incredible right and then
you just click play right and the market
goes let's see what it does okay we're
trading on the second of J which is not
a good which is not a good uh place to
trade but again like let's just play
forward and again you manage your trade
boom boom very chop okay we hit stop and
right now there is no way back you're
are down 1% that's it you cannot say
well I would have taken a break even on
that trade no you did not because if you
would have you would have moved your
stop loss to break even okay and now
what you simply do is okay I took the
stop you again click here copy image and
you mark this up you take note of this
trade in your notion template and then
again what I simply like to do is if I'm
just trading London session I'd like to
go back to the next London session okay
so again still here we're still bullish
so let's try to take another long you
wait start pressing - minute candles and
uh yeah the market just massively dumped
and again no trade the market just dumps
right now if if you don't want to take
any trades then you just don't take a
trade and again you go to the next Lon
session but now again follow with your
hard time frames again you delete the
old stuff make sure to take note of it
in notion we have a 4ly trend change
down there we have a brand new 4ly
Supply the market is right now at a
lower low so we can expect potentially
some Longs but we can also expect
continuations lower okay the market is
still traveling towards the 50% a lot of
imbalance and you can see it's like
you're actually really trading you have
to wait for it you cannot just press
forward because here you cannot go back
let's say I want to actually go back and
take a short here you cannot go back
there is no way to go back and actually
pretend you took the trade if you missed
the trade you missed it forever right
and then again you have to be really
careful right so for example in this
case the Market opens manipulates okay
the market very nicely pushed up a field
imbalance I want to take a short but
then maybe you go to the 5 minute time
from here I want to wait for let's say
for a trend change there is the trend
change so am I going to enter from here
exactly or am I going to be looking for
some sort of a pullback well let's say I
enter from here and I'm going to Target
the Asian low so click on your two place
order then I'm just going to do Market
you click save and now you are in the
trade there is no coming back if it hits
stop loss it hits stop loss if maybe it
gives gives you a little pullback to
take a better entry you can scale in but
you cannot change your entry because
you're already in right and then you
just allow for the market to play out
and see what happens again I'm trading
again this is not a back testing session
right there because we're trading at the
worst time there is we're Ste in the
trade right you can see we're Ste in the
trade so right now you can choose to
manage it you can choose to go break
even you can choose to close your trade
because you think the market might
reverse you can you can you are just
here making decisions right and again
you just play Let's see what happens
today okay um wait a little bit we take
out the asan high I'm looking for I'm
still bearish and again you look for
that Trend change there is the trend
change now if you decide to take a short
from here you decide how to take it are
you going to take it with a limit here
and a stop loss above and then of course
you let's say we target that same same
thing let's see you click here place
order then you click on a limit because
we're setting a limit right there and
then you just click play there you go
we're into the trade stop loss above and
you just allow it to play out W nice and
again like in this case you can decide
to close partials so you simply click
here on the X based on the trade so I'm
not sure how we actually because we took
the TR the two trades from the same
direction so I'm not sure how it
separates them but if you click here you
can choose how many partials to close
like let's say I want to close 80%
partials you click save right and now
80% is closed and then of course you
just play there is our take profit and
everything is closed right then again
you click on the trade copy image you go
back to the voyage actually explain okay
the market was at a lower high uh it I
expected lower downside so again this is
why I took this trade with a 50-minute
trend change with a limit from The
50-minute Zone take notes okay and now
as you go through a lot of this trade
again this is not a back testing session
I'm not here to teach you a strategy or
anything else let me know if you would
like me to do that now here under the
strategy you're going to get all of your
insights so if you click here you're
going to see uh your total p&l you're
going to see your win rate you're going
to see the total trades your average R
to reward your max Roost to reward on
your trades ideal average Max ideal
again I'm still kind of exploring it but
you get all of these stats again you can
see loss streak Max loss streak duration
of your trade your average loss your
average win how many win streak you have
exact the things that I told you to take
note of it already offers it what did I
tell you about the days right as you get
100 trades I promise you you're going to
see which days work the best you
actually see here the profits you make
per day right and if I actually show you
let's say um uh some stuff that I'm back
testing let's say this for example when
you click you get more data you see your
Equity curve you see how much percentage
you've had you see your win rate you see
again in this case you can see the rest
reward I take the average is 2.5 well
I'm getting like the max I'm getting is
six so I can definitely look to increase
my risk to reward right Max losing
streak six trades so I know that I'm
when I'm trading this uh setup live I
know that I can get six traes loses in a
row and I know that after five uh
winners in a row I can potentially get
some losses here you can see by day so
what I see is that Monday is one of my
most profitable days right Wednesday
50/50 right Friday Also 50/50 so what I
consider trading Wednesday and Friday
probably not here again you can see the
total performance per month here you can
see every day that you took and the
result during that day you you can see
like for example in in May I only took
three trades and again this makes me
think long term because if I have like
two to three weeks without a trade I am
calm and I'm not going to rush into
doing anything stupid so that is FX
replay definitely uh recommend getting
this because this is the closest you can
get to real trading with real execution
and with real stats so make sure you do
that all right Fanatics I really hope
you enjoyed this video make sure to let
me know down in the comments if you did
let me know what you actually learned
from it and what is your plan of action
going forward with back testing forward
testing and also Gathering your data hit
the thumbs up in order to help uh spread
this video out and make sure to grab
your nocean template down in the
description and make sure to join FX
replay with the code trading fanatic 15
so you can get some discount and of
course take your back testing to the
next level of course if you need
anything else let me know down in the
comments for another topic that you want
me to talk about and again I love you
guys and talk to you in the next one
bye-bye